Stephen Seator

Senior Front-End Engineer & UX Designer Marlton, NJ. 08053 (609) 417-7890 steve.seator@gmail.com

Employment

Comcast

Senior UX Designer

Philadelphia, PA (2019 - Current)

- Conduct, analyze, and document end-user research using qualitative and quantitative methods to align business objectives with user community needs
- Communicate a unified strategy for implementation involving business stakeholders and component teams through creation of user journey maps, flow diagrams, interactive prototypes, low and high fidelity wireframes
- Lead contributor and maintainer of an internal design system, documenting technical & layout specifications, interaction details, typography and aesthetics
- Management of standards and procedures meant to empower collaboration and ensure smooth delivery of business critical artifacts and deliverables with predictable cadence

Comcast

Senior Front-End Engineer

Philadelphia, PA (2017 - 2019)

- Lead of a newly organized front-end team tasked with creating a web interface for an internal platform featuring network automation and orchestration.
- Responsible for selection of front-end frameworks, tooling, project architecture, system design, build process and deployment pipeline.
- Conceptualized and communicated product vision to internal stakeholders, component teams and end users through presentations, mockups and prototypes
- Led development and deployment of several business critical features requiring complex domain-specific knowledge within 6 months of formation
- Management and coordination of tasks to team members, promoting individual product ownership and buy-in of development strategy and process

Local Wisdom

UI Developer

Raritan, NJ (2013 - 2017)

- Development of branded pharmaceutical sales presentations and interactive visual aids for web & iPad
- Utilize HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, JSON, AJAX and additional open-source technologies to create engaging, dynamic interactive experiences
- Creation and enhancement of proprietary JavaScript libraries and modules to facilitate consistent and reusable product templates
- Interfaced with agencies to establish product expectations and define development specifications
- Modified existing and created new media assets required for implementation as necessary

(More employment history available upon request)

Profile

Bringing years of product development experience across various industries with a rich professional history in both application development and human-centered design. Wielding a balance of discipline and empathy to deliver real business value with quality, consistency and timeliness.

Commands a strong proficiency with front-end technologies utilizing open-source frameworks, libraries, design packages, bundlers, and other industray-standard toolkits to enhance productivity and facilitate streamlined work-flows.

Prioritizes evidence-based solutions founded via research and analysis to satisfy end-user and stakeholder needs.

Comprehensively designs and crafts engaging and delightful experiences from initial conception to final deployment.

Skills



Education

Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ (2002 - 2004)

- Studies focused in business, economics and computer science
- Performed contract work for various mobile application developers in tandem to primary studies

Ursinus College

Collegeville, PA (2000 - 2002)

- Major studies in mathematics and computer science
- Assumed resident assistant role through sophomore year